in this video we're going to talk about
segments and accounts in GP and then
look at how that information can be
migrated and used in business
Central an organization's chart of
accounts is made up of a list of natural
accounts sometimes called main accounts
most companies want to be able to
analyze transactions that are posted to
their natural accounts categorizing
transactions can help to better
understand a company's expenses and
revenues primarily their profit and loss
accounts companies may want to C
categorize Revenue by region and Market
segment and expenses by department and
projects this can be done through the
use of segments and GP and dimensions in
business
Central first let's go to the account
format in GP and see how segments and
the main account are defined the account
format is created using a combination of
segments and the main account the
account format will be used to build out
the chart of accounts we currently have
our format broken into three different
segments including division account and
Department each have a specific position
and length in the
format next let's look at the segments
and what the values are for those
segments if I select my division segment
I can then click on the lookup to see
all the various divisions that I've set
up in my
organization finally if we go to the
account window we can see how the
account format is used to build out the
chart of accounts
if we pull up our
36520 account we can see that this is
the travel expense account for our sales
division now let's look at how the main
account and segments can be migrated to
business
Central in the cloud migration Setup
Wizard you can indicate which segments
you would like to be Global Dimensions
similar to segments dimensions and
business Central let you categorize and
analyze transactions posted to the chart
of accounts instead of creating separate
ledger accounts for each division or
Department Dimensions can be used in
combination with your main account to
analyze information and reduce the need
for large and complex chart of accounts
business Central has two Global
Dimensions these should be the most
common segments as you can easily sort
and filter on these Dimensions the
remainder of your segments will be
migrated as shortcut
dimensions in business Central let's see
where those global and shortcut
dimensions are defined
to navigate to the general ledger setup
we will select the search icon and enter
general ledger setup and choose that
from the search
results in this setup window we can see
that the division and Department
segments I selected in the cloud
migration have been set up as Global
Dimensions if I had more than those
segments in GP the remaining segments
would have come over as shortcut
dimensions in business
Central next let's navigate to the
dimension window where you can see these
existing dimensions and create new ones
later on should you want to start
analyzing additional information in
business
Central if I select my division
Dimension and go to Dimension values I
can see all my segment values from GP
have been migrated over I could also
create additional ones in the
future finally let's see how the chart
of accounts looks in business Central
now that it's been migrating
over in my chart of accounts all the
main accounts that I had defined in GP
are now my chart of accounts and I can
still see all my transaction amounts by
the various segments let's again look at
that trible expense account that we had
looked at in
GP if I want to drill back on the
balance I can see all my department and
division segments with the amounts
broken out for each similar to how it
looks in
GP and that's a quick look at segments
and dimensions in GP and business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources